DANIEL CHOINIERE

7608 Landau Dr, Bloomington, MN 55438 · 651.208.2707 dchoinie@gmail.com · in/daniel-choiniere/· dchoinie.github.io

Multi-talented web developer and digital marketing specialist with 8+ years of professional experience (2 years of development experience) seeking full time developer position. Highly motivated to begin contributing to a high-performing team and expanding my technical skill set.

EXPERIENCE

NOV. 2014 - CURRENT

RECORD LABEL ASSOCIATE, K-TEL INTERNATIONAL, LTD

- Developed E-Commerce website utilizing the Shopify platform resulting in 60% increase in online sales.
- Design and develop custom landing pages for email marketing & social media campaigns.
- Use 3rd party tools to create online registration forms with advanced features.
- Implemented use of Google Analytics and Facebook Pixel to track website conversions.
- Create & distribute email marketing campaigns resulting in 35% increase in subscribers.
- Head of paid advertising through Google Adwords & Facebook Ads Manager.
- Social media marketing including basic graphic design, general strategy and establishment of best-practices for all major platforms.

SEPT. 2011 - CURRENT

TENNIS PROFESSIONAL | DEVELOPER, PUBLICINDOORTENNIS.COM

- Led initiative to overhaul entire front end of company website to optimize UX.
- Worked directly with owner to determine project scope and create mock ups of proposed UI / UX.
- Leveraged the Bootstrap framework to transform front end elements to be responsive to all screen sizes.
- Lead group & private instructional classes ranging in age from 6 65+.

JUNE 2016 - CURRENT

FREELANCE WEB DEVELOPER

- Leveraged the WordPress CMS to create multiple small business and non-profit websites.
- Assist clients in gathering media assets and general web design.
- Utilize 3rd party tools as solutions to unique website requirements (ex. paid memberships).
- Perform online marketing services, including social media and industry-specific services.

EDUCATION

APRIL 2013

A.A.S IN MUSIC BUSINESS, MCNALLY SMITH COLLEGE OF MUSIC

Dean's List 2013

2006 - 2009

GUSTAVUS ADOLPHUS COLLEGE

2017 - 2018

TEAMTREEHOUSE.COM

SKILLS

- Front-End Languages: HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax
- Tools: GitHub, WordPress, Shopify, Visual Studio, Sublime Text, Atom
- Marketing: Google Adwords certified, Facebook business & ads manager, MailChimp, Google Analytics, Facebook Pixel, Trello, HootSuite
- Frameworks: Bootstrap, UIKit, Foundation, Angular, React
- In-Progress: PHP, MySQL, Node, C#

REFERENCES

Available upon request.